You can talk to me, we can laugh and smile
Eikaiwa Time Trial
Let's get started with Day 9 for the month of October.
Hi everyone, I'm Steve Sareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
Kyou mokyoubi wa, konshuu renshu shita hyougen o
jissai no kaewa de tsukaeru you ni treinin shite kimasu.
Okay, let's get started.
Express, Create, Reply
まずはウォーミングアップをしましょう。
今からジェニーさんが今週練習した表現をランダムに言ってくれますので、
何も見ないで全部リピートできるかチャレンジしてみてください。
ジェニーさんのイントネーションも真似してみてください。
So try to say it quickly and smoothly.
And copy my intonation.
Okay, here we go.
What dish did you bring?
I brought yakisoba.
The plates are here.
Here are the serving chopsticks.
You can add this seasoning if you like.
Does it have sugar in it?
My daughter is a picky eater.
All right.
Did you express all those phrases quickly and smoothly?
And now, let's move on to the next step.
Step 2. Create.
続いては今週練習したフレーズを使ってオリジナルの英文を作ってみましょう。
まずはこちら。
何々をご自由にお召し上がりください。
Help yourself to 何々。
料理名を入れてそれを自由に取るように呼びかけましょう。
飲み物でもいいですよ。
Are you ready?
では、Help yourself to どうぞ。
Good.
では、ジェニーさんの番です。
聞いてみましょう。
ジェニー。
Help yourself to some coffee.
飲み物でしたね。
では、同じフレーズを使って、
もう一度文を作ってみてください。
Now try to create one more sentence.
Help yourself to...
どうぞ。
Alright, let's move on to the second phrase.
It has 〜が入っています。
It has 〜 in it.
Let's make a sentence to tell you what ingredients and seasonings are in the dish.
You can use multiple ingredients.
It has 〜
Here you go.
OK, it's Jenny's turn.
It has cheese, tomatoes, and basil in it.
Cheese, tomatoes, and basil.
Basil.
What is it, Jenny?
It's one of my favorite salads.
Salad.
That's a good one.
So, everyone, let's make a sentence using it has 〜 in it one more time.
Here we go.
It has 〜.
Here you go.
Good job.
では、三つ目です。
この料理に何々は入っていません。
This dish doesn't have any 〜 in it.
食材や調味料について、それが料理に入っていないことを伝えましょう。
お使ってどうぞ。
All right, Jenny, it's your turn.
This dish doesn't have any meat in it.
That's a good one.
それでは、もう一度文を作りましょう。
This dish doesn't have any...
どうぞ。
All right, you did it.
Now let's move on to our final step.
Step 3. Reply.
さらに実践的なトレーニングをしましょう。
僕の英語の問いかけに対して、英語で自由に返答してください。
まず一つ目。
普段肉を食べるか聞きます。
Are you a meat eater?
YesやNoなどに一言付け足して答えてみてください。
You can do it!
いきます。
Are you a meat eater?
では、返答例を聞きましょう。
Are you a meat-eater?
Yes, I have meat all the time.
Yesの後に、私はいつも、all the time、肉ばかりを食べています。
I have meat all the time.
では、もう一度、同じ問いかけに答えてみましょう。
Are you a meat-eater?
Yes.
それでは二つ目です。想像してください。あなたは僕と料理持ち寄りのピクニックにやってきました。そこでこう聞きます。
What dish did you bring? 何の料理を持ってきたのか、そしてそれがどんな料理かも含めて答えてみてください。準備はいいですか?
What dish did you bring?
では、返答例です。
I brought stir-fried noodles.
This dish is called yakisoba.
焼きそばの上手な紹介の方法ですね。
I brought stir-fried noodles.
This dish is called yakisoba.
簡単に答えられますね。
では、もう一度答えてみましょう。
What dish did you bring?
それでは最後の問いかけです あなたが持ってきた料理について何が入っているか聞きます
What's in it? 食材や調味料など入っているものを説明してみましょう
OK, are you ready? Here's the question
What's in it? どうぞ
では、ジェニーさんの返答例を聞きましょう。
What's in it?
It has vegetables, pork, and noodles in it.
And you can put some nori on it if you like.
焼きそばについての説明ですね。
It has vegetables, pork, and noodles in it.
お好みで、のりをかけてもいいですよ。
You can put some nori on it if you like.
That's a great one.
では、最後にもう一度、あなたの料理について答えてください。
What's in it?
Okay, time's up.
Great job today, everyone.
さて、明日は対話カラオケです。
Conversation partner の野良さんがピクニックに招待してくれます。
食べ物について楽しく会話をしてみましょう
So just use the phrases that we practiced this week
You'll have a fun picnic
So everyone, get on board
And let's practice speaking together
See you next time on
Eikaiwa Time Trial
Bye-bye